Okay.
Uh
Cameras are rolling. This is lecture 14.
Starting a new chapter.
Chapter about orthogonality.
What it means for vectors to be
orthogonal.
What it means for subspaces to be
orthogonal. What it means for bases to
be orthogonal.
So, a 90° This is
This is a 90° chapter.
So, what does it mean?
Uh let me let me jump to subspaces
because I've drawn here
the big picture. This is the
This is the 1806 picture here.
And
uh
Hold it down, guys.
Uh so, this is the picture and we know a
lot about that picture already.
We know the dimension of every subspace.
We know that these dimensions are
r and n minus r.
We know that these dimensions are r and
m minus r.
What we
What I want to show now is what this
figure is saying
that
the angle betw- wait, the figure is like
just my attempt to draw what I'm now
going to say that
the angle between these subspaces is
90°.
And the angle between these subspaces is
90°. Now, I have to say, what does that
mean? What does it mean for a subspaces
to be orthogonal?
But I hope you appreciate the
beauty of this picture.
That that
those subspaces are going to come out to
be orthogonal.
Those two and also those two.
So that's like
one point
one important point to step forward in
understanding those subspaces.
We knew what each subspace was like. We
could compute bases for them. Now we
know more.
Or we will in a few minutes.
Okay, I have to say
first of all, what does it mean for two
vectors to be orthogonal?
So let me start with that.
Orthogonal vectors.
The word orthogonal is is just another
word for perpendicular.
It means that in n-dimensional space
the angle between those vectors is 90°.
It means that they form a right
triangle.
It It even means that the going way back
to the Greeks
that this
uh angle that this triangle of vector x
of vector y
and the vector x + y
of course that'll be the
hypotenuse.
So what was it the Greeks figured out
and it's
neat.
It's the fact that the
So
these are orthogonal. This is a right
angle. If So So let me put the great
name down, Pythagoras.
I'm I'm looking for What am I looking
for?
I'm looking for the condition
if you give me two vectors, how do I
know if they're orthogonal?
How can I tell two perpendicular
vectors? And actually, you probably know
the answer. Let me write the answer
down. Orthogonal vectors, what's the
test for orthogonality?
I take the dot product,
which I tend to write as X transpose Y,
cuz that's a row times a column,
and that matrix multiplication just
gives me the right thing, that X1Y1 +
X2Y2 and so on.
So, these vectors are orthogonal if this
result X transpose Y is
zero.
That's the test.
Okay.
Can I connect that
to other things?
I mean, it's like it's amazing. It's
It's just beautiful that here we have
and we're in N dimensions,
we've got a couple of vectors, we want
to know the angle between them,
and the right thing to look at is
the simplest thing that you could
imagine, the dot product. Okay. Now,
why? So, I'm answering the question now,
why let's just some
Let's add some uh
justification to this fact that that's
the test. Okay.
So, Pythagoras would say we've got a
right triangle if that length squared
plus that length squared equals that
length squared.
Okay. Can I write it as
X squared
plus y squared
equals
x plus y squared.
Now, don't please don't think that this
is always true.
This is only going to be true
in this
It's going to be
equivalent to orthogonality. For other
triangles, of course, it's not true.
For other triangles, it's not. But for a
right triangle, somehow that fact should
connect to that fact. Can we just make
that connection?
What's the connection between this test
for orthogonality and this
statement of orthogonality? Well, I
guess I have to say, what is the length
squared?
So, let's
continue on the
board underneath with that equation.
Give me another way to express the
length squared of a vector.
And let me just give you a vector.
The vector 1 2 3.
That's in three dimensions.
What is the length squared of the vector
x equal 1 2 3?
So, how do you find the length squared?
Well, really you're just
you want the length of that vector that
goes along one, up two, and out three.
And And we'll
come come back to that right triangle
stuff.
The length squared is This is exactly
x transpose x.
Whenever I see x transpose x, I know
I've got
a number that's positive.
It's a length squared unless it unless x
happens to be the zero vector. That's
the one case where the length is zero.
So, right this is just X1 squared plus
X2 squared plus so on plus Xn squared.
So, one in the example I gave you, what
was the length squared of that vector 1
2 3?
So, you square those, you get 1 4 and 9,
you add, you get 14.
So, the vector 1 2 3 has length 14.
So, let me just let me just put down a
vector here.
Let X be the vector 1 2 3.
Let me cook up a vector that's
orthogonal to it.
So, what's the vector that's orthogonal
So, let
write down here X squared is 1 plus 4
plus 9 14.
Let me cook up a vector that's
orthogonal to it.
We'll get
Right, that that those two vectors are
orthogonal. The length of Y squared is
five.
And X plus Y
is
1 and 2 making 3, 2 and minus 1 making
1, 3 and 0 making 3, and the length of
this squared
is 9 plus 1 plus 9 19.
And sure enough
I haven't proved anything. I've just
like
checked to see that my my my test X
transpose Y equals 0, which is true,
right? Everybody sees that X transpose Y
is 0 here.
That that's maybe the main point that
you should get really quick at doing X
transpose Y. So, it's just
this plus this plus this, and that's
zero.
And sure enough, that clicks with
uh 14 + 5 agreeing with 19. Now, let me
just do that in letters.
So, that's Y transpose Y.
And this is
X + Y
transpose X + Y.
Okay.
So, I'm looking again, this isn't always
true. I repeat.
This is going to be true when we have a
right angle.
And let's just Well, of course, I'm just
going to simplify this stuff here.
There's an X transpose X there,
and there's a Y transpose Y there,
and there's an X transpose Y,
and there's a Y transpose X.
I knew I could
do that simplification because
I'm just doing matrix multiplication,
and I've just followed the rules. Okay.
So, X transpose X is cancelled, Y
transpose Y is cancelled, and what about
these guys? What can What can you tell
me about
the inner product of X with Y and the
inner product of Y with X?
Is there a difference?
I think if we if while we're doing real
vectors, which is all we're doing now,
there isn't a difference. There's no
difference. If I take X transpose Y,
that'll give me zero. If I took Y
transpose X, I would have the same
X1Y1 and X2Y2 and X3Y3.
It would be the same. So, this is this
is this is the same as that. This is
really all I'll knock that guy out and
say two of these.
So, actually that's the
this this equation boiled down to this
thing being zero.
Right?
Everything else canceled and this
equation boiled down to that one. So,
that's really all I wanted.
I just wanted to check that
Pythagoras
for a right triangle
led me
to this Now, of course, I canceled the
two now, no problem.
2x transpose y = 0 as the test.
Fair enough. Okay.
You knew it was coming.
The dot product of orthogonal vectors is
zero.
It's just I just want to say that's
really neat. It comes that it comes out
so well. All right.
Now, what about So, now I know if two
vec what it means when two vectors are
orthogonal. By the way, what about if
one of these guys is the zero vector?
Suppose x is the zero vector and y is
whatever.
Are they orthogonal?
Sure.
In math, the one thing about math is
you're supposed to follow the rules.
So, you're supposed to If If x is the
zero vector, you're supposed to take the
zero vector dotted with y and of course,
you get always get zero.
So, just so we're all
sure, the zero vector is orthogonal to
everybody.
But
what I want to
what I I want to
uh
speak about is subspaces.
What does it mean
for me to say
that some subspace is orthogonal to some
other subspace?
So, okay. Now, I've got to write this
down. So, cuz we're defining definition
of subspace
S
is
orthogonal, so
to
subspace
let's say T.
So, I've got a couple of subspaces.
And what should it mean for those guys
to be orthogonal?
It's just a na- it's sort of what's the
natural extension from orthogonal
vectors to orthogonal subspaces?
Well,
and in particular
let's think of some orthogonal subspaces
like
uh
uh this wall.
I I let's say in three dimensions.
So, the blackboard extended to infinity,
right? Is a is a subspace,
a plane, a two-dimensional subspace.
It's a little bumpy, but anyway, it's a
think of it as a subspace.
Um
let me take the floor as another
subspace.
Again,
it's not
a great subspace. MIT only built it like
so-so, but uh
and I'll put the origin right here.
So, the origin of the world
is right there.
Okay.
Thereby giving linear algebra its proper
importance in in this. Okay. So, there's
one subspace, there's another one, the
floor.
And
are they orthogonal?
What does it mean for two subspaces to
be orthogonal in a and in that special
case, are they orthogonal? All right.
Let let's finish this sentence.
What does it mean? Means
We have to We have to know what we're
talking about here.
So, what would be a reasonable idea of
orthogonal?
Well, let me
put the right thing up.
It means that every vector in S
every
vector
in S
is orthogonal
to
to What am I going to say?
Every vector in T.
That
That's a reasonable
and it's a good and it's the right
definition for two subspaces to be
orthogonal.
But I just want you to see, hey, what
does that mean?
So, answer the question about the
the blackboard and the
floor.
Are those two subspaces They're They're
two-dimensional, right?
And we're in R3.
It's like the
XZ plane or something and the XY plane.
Are they orthogonal?
Is every vector in the blackboard
orthogonal to vector in the floor?
Starting from the origin right there.
Yes or no? I could take a vote.
I'll be getting some yeses and some nos.
No is the answer. They're not.
You can tell me a vector
in the blackboard and a vector in the
floor that are not orthogonal.
Uh
What's What's Well, you can tell me
quite a few, I guess.
Maybe like I could take some 45° guy in
the
blackboard and some
thing in the floor
that aren't at 90°, right? In fact, even
more, you could tell me a vector
that's in both the blackboard plane and
the floor plane, so it's certainly not
orthogonal to itself.
So, for sure, those two planes aren't
orthogonal.
What would that be? So, what's a vector
that's in the black- in in both of those
planes?
It's this guy running along the crack
there, where the intersection
the intersection.
A vector Look,
if two subspaces meet some vector, well,
then for sure they're not orthogonal
because
that vector is in one and it's in the
other and it's not orthogonal to itself
unless it's zero. So, the only I mean,
so orthogonal
If for me to say these two subspaces are
orthogonal, first of all,
I'm certainly saying that they don't
intersect in any
uh nonzero vector.
But also,
I mean more than that just not
intersecting isn't good enough. So, give
me an example
Oh, let's say in the plane.
Well, well.
Well,
when do we have orthogonal subspaces in
the plane? Yeah, tell me in the plane.
So, we don't there aren't that many
different subspaces in the plane. What
What have we got in the plane that's as
possible subspaces?
The zero vector,
real small,
uh a line through the origin,
or the whole plane.
Okay. Now, so when is a line through the
origin
orthogonal to the whole plane?
Never, right? Never.
When is a line through the origin
orthogonal to the zero subspace?
Always. Right.
When is a line through the origin
orthogonal to a different line through
the origin? Well, that's the case that
we all have a clear picture of. They
the two lines have to meet at 90°. They
have only the
So, that So, that's
like this simple case I'm talking about.
There's one subspace, there's the other
subspace, they only meet at zero, and
they're orthogonal. Okay.
Now,
so we now know what it means for two
subspaces to be orthogonal. And now I
want to say
that this is true for the row space and
the null space.
Okay. So, that's the
that's the
neat fact.
So, row space
is
orthogonal
to the null space. Now, how did I come
up with that?
But, you see that like it's right. That
means that these that these subspaces
are just the right things. They're just
cutting the cutting the whole space up
into
two perpendicular subspaces.
Okay, so what?
Well, what have I got
to work with?
All I know is the null space.
The null space has vectors that solve
Ax = 0.
So, this is a this is a guy x.
x is in the null space.
Then, Ax is 0.
So, why is it orthogonal to the rows of
A?
If I write down Ax = 0, which is all I
know about the null space,
then
I guess I want you to see that that's
telling me just that equation right
there is telling me
that the rows of A, let me write it out.
There's row one
of A.
Row two.
Row m.
of A. That that's A.
And it's multiplying x
and it's producing
zero.
Okay.
Written out that way,
you'll see it.
So, I'm saying that a vector in the row
space is perpendicular to this guy x in
the null space.
And you see why?
Cuz this equation is telling you that
the row one of A
multiplying, that's a that's a dot
product, right? Row row one of A dot
product with this X is producing this
zero.
So, X is orthogonal to the first row.
And to the second row. Row two of A X is
giving that zero. Row M of A times X is
giving that zero. So, X is
The equation is telling me that X is
orthogonal to all the rows.
Right? It's just sitting there.
That's all we we it had to be sitting
there cuz we didn't know anything more
about the null space than this.
And now I guess to be totally
complete here,
I've now checked that X is orthogonal to
each separate row.
But what else
strictly speaking do I have to do?
The the what to show that those
subspaces are orthogonal, I have to take
this X in the null space and show that
it's orthogonal to every
vector in the row space. Every vector in
the row space. So, what what else is in
the row space?
Th- this row is in the row space, that
row is in the row space.
They They're all there. But that's not
the whole row space, right? We just have
to like remember, what does it mean
What does that word space telling us?
And what else is in the row space?
Besides the rows?
All there
combination.
So, I really have to check that sure
enough, if X is perpendicular row one,
row two, all the all the different
separate rows, then also X is
perpendicular to what combination of the
rows. And that's just matrix
multiplication again. You know, I have
row one
transpose X is zero.
So on, row two transpose X is zero.
So, I'm entitled to multiply that by
some C1, this by some C2, I still have
zeros. I'm entitled to add.
So, I have C1 row one. So So, all this
when I put that together, that's
big parentheses C1 row one plus C2 row
two and so on
transpose X is zero.
Right? I just added the zeros and got
zero, and I just added these following
the rules.
No
No big deal. The whole point was right
sitting in that.
Okay.
So
if I come back to this figure now
I'm
like a happier person.
Cuz I have
this
uh
the I now see how those subspaces are
oriented.
And these subspaces are also oriented.
Well, actually
why why is that orthogonality?
Well, if the same statement for A
transpose as that one was for A. So, I
won't take time to prove it again
because it's
cuz we checked it for every matrix, and
A transpose is just as good a matrix as
A, so
we're orthogonal over there.
So, we really have
carved up this
these this This was like carving up M
dimensional space
into two subspaces.
And this one was carving up
n-dimensional space
into two subspaces.
And
Well, one more thing here. One more
important thing.
Let Let me move into into into three
dimensions.
Tell me a couple of orthogonal subspaces
in three dimensions
that
somehow don't carve up the whole space.
There's stuff left there.
I'm thinking of a couple of orthogonal
lines.
If I
Suppose I'm in three dimensions, R3.
And I have one line, one one-dimensional
subspace, and a perpendicular one.
Could those be
the row space and the null space?
Could those be the row space and the
null space? Could I Could I be in three
dimensions
and have a row space that's a line and a
null space that's a line?
No.
Why not?
Because the dimensions aren't right,
right? The dimensions are no good. The
The dimensions here are r and n minus r.
They add up to three. They add up to n.
If I take uh Let's just if I just follow
that example.
If If If If the row space is
one-dimensional, suppose A is What's a
good
in I'm in R3. I want a one-dimensional
row space. Let me take 1 2 5 2 4 10.
What's the dimension of that row space?
One.
What's the dimension of the null space?
What What tell What's the null space
look like in that case? The row space is
a line, right? One-dimensional. It's
just a line through 1 2 5.
Geometrically, what's the row space look
like?
It's a
What's its dimension?
So So here are Here n is 3.
The rank is 1.
So the dimension of the null space, so
I'm looking
at this x
x1 x2 x3
to get 0.
So the dimension of the null space is
we all know is
two.
Right. It's a plane.
And now, actually, we know we see better
what plane is it.
What plane is it?
It's the plane that's perpendicular to
1 2 5.
Right? We now see In fact, the 2 4 10
didn't actually have any effect at all.
I could have just ignored that.
That didn't change the row space or the
null space.
I'll just make that
one equation.
Yeah. Okay. Sure.
That's That's the easiest to deal with.
One equation,
three unknowns,
and um
I want to ask
uh
What's What does the equation give me?
It gives me the null space.
And you would have said
back in September, you would have said
it gives you a plane.
And
we're we're completely right. And the
plane it gives you, the normal vector,
you remember in calculus there was this
dumb normal vector called N. Well, there
it is, 1 2 5.
Okay.
So,
uh
What what is the
What's the point I want to make here?
I want to make I want to emphasize that
not only are the
Let me write it in words.
So, I want to write the null space
and the row space
are
orthogonal.
That's That's this neat fact which we we
just checked from AX = 0. But now I want
to say
I want to say more because there's a
little more that's true.
Their dimensions add to the whole space.
So, that's like a little extra
information.
That
It's not like I could I couldn't have a
line and a line in three dimensions.
Those Those don't add up. One and one
don't add to three.
So, I use the word orthogonal
complement.
in
Rn. And the idea of this word complement
is
that
the orthogonal complement of a
row space
contains not just some vectors that are
orthogonal to it, but all.
So, so what does that mean? That means
that the null space
contains all
not just some, but all vectors
that are perpendicular to the row space.
Okay.
Really, what I've done in this half of
the lecture
is just
notice
some of the nice geometry that that we
didn't pick up before because we didn't
discuss perpendicular vectors before.
But, it was all sitting there, and now
we've picked it up. That these vectors
are orthogonal complements. And I guess
I even call this
part one of the fundamental theorem of
linear algebra.
The fundamental theorem of linear
algebra
is about these four subspaces.
So, part one is about their dimension.
Maybe I should call it part two now.
Their dimensions we got.
Now we're getting their orthogonality.
That's part two.
And part three
will be about bases for this.
Orthogonal bases.
So, that's
uh coming up.
Okay.
So,
I'm I'm uh
I'm happy with that
geometry right now.
Okay.
Okay. Now, what's my next goal in this
chapter?
Here's the It's the main problem of the
chapter.
The main problem of the chapter is So,
this is coming.
Coming attraction.
This is this is the very last chapter
that's about AX = B.
I would like to solve that
system of equations
when there is no solution.
You may say what a ridiculous thing to
do, but I have to say I it's done all
the time.
In fact, it has to be done. You get
So so the problem is solve
as the best possible
solve I'll put quotes
AX = B when
there is
no solution.
And of course, what does that mean? B
isn't in the in the column space.
And it's quite typical
if this matrix A is rectangular, if I
maybe I have M equations
and that's bigger than the number of
unknowns
then for sure the rank
is
not M.
The rank couldn't be M now. So there
will be a lot of right hand sides with
no solution, but
Here's an example.
Some satellite is buzzing along.
You measure its position.
You make a thousand measurements.
So that gives you a thousand equations
for the
for the parameters that that that give
the position.
But there aren't a thousand parameters,
there's just maybe six or so.
Or you're measuring the
you're doing questionnaires.
You're you're measuring
resistances.
You're taking pulses. You're measuring
somebody's pulse rate.
Okay, there's just one unknown, the
pulse rate.
So, you measure it once, okay, fine.
But, if you really want to know it, you
measure it multiple times.
But then, the measurements have no
reason. So, there's
The problem is that in many, many
problems, we got too many equations,
and they've got noise in the right-hand
side. So,
Ax = b,
I can't expect to solve it exactly,
right? Cuz I don't even know what the
there's error there's there's
measurement
mistake in b,
but there's information, too.
There's a lot of information about x in
there. And what I want to do is like
separate the noise, the junk,
from the information.
And so, this is a straightforward linear
algebra problem.
How do I solve What's the best solution?
Okay.
Now,
let me
um
I want I I want to say, so that's like
describes the problem in a
algebraic way. I've got some equations.
I'm looking for the best solution. Well,
one way to find it is one one way to
start
one way to find a solution is
throw away
equations until you've got a nice square
invertible system and solve that.
That's not satisfactory.
There's no reason
in these measurements to say these
measurements are perfect and these
measurements are useless.
We want to use all the measurements to
get the best information, to get the
maximum information. But how? Okay.
Let me anticipate a matrix that's going
to show up.
This A is typically a rectangle.
But a matrix that shows up whenever you
have and we've chapter three was all
about rectangular matrices.
And we know when this is solvable, you
could do elimination on it, right?
But I'm thinking, hey, you do
elimination and you get equation zero
equal
other non-zeros. I'm thinking we really
elimination is going to fail.
So, that's our question. Elimination
will get us down to
to will tell us if there is a solution
or not, but I'm now thinking not.
Okay, so what are we going to do? All
right. I'm going to I'm going to tell
you
to jump ahead
to the matrix that will play a key role.
So, this is the matrix that you want to
understand for this chapter four.
And it's the matrix A transpose A.
What's
Tell me some things about that matrix.
So, A is this m by n matrix,
rectangular.
But now I'm saying that the good matrix
that shows up in the end is A transpose
A. So, tell me something about that.
Is it Yeah, tell me what's the first
thing you know about A transpose A?
It's square, right?
Square because this is m by n
and this is n by m.
So, this is the result is n by n. Good.
Square.
What else?
It's symmetric. Good. It's symmetric.
Cuz you remember how to do that. If we
transpose that matrix,
let's transpose it.
A transpose A, if I transpose it,
then
that comes first, transpose, this comes
second,
transpose,
and then transposing twice is
leaves it brings it back to the same, so
it's symmetric. Good.
Now,
we now know how to ask more about a
matrix.
I'm interested in
is it invertible?
If not, what's its null space?
So, I want to know about cuz cuz you're
going to see Well, let me let me even
Well, I shouldn't do this, but I will.
Let me tell you what equation to solve
when you can't solve that one.
The good equation
comes from multiplying both sides by A
transpose.
So, the the the good equation that you
get to
is this one. A transpose A x = A
transpose B.
That will be the central equation in the
chapter.
So, I think why not tell it to
Why not admit it right away?
Okay.
I have to I should really give X
uh I
I want to sort of indicate that this X
isn't I mean this X
was the solution to that equation if it
existed, but probably didn't.
Now, let me give this
a different name, X hat.
Because I'm hoping
this one will have a solution.
And I'm saying that it's my best
solution.
I'll have to say what does best mean.
But that's going to be my my my plan.
I'm going to say that the best solution
solves this equation. So, you see right
away why I'm so interested in this
matrix A transpose A and in its
invertibility.
Okay.
Now, when is it invertible?
Let me take a case Let Let me just do
one example and then
uh
uh just I I'll just pick a matrix here.
Just so we see what A transpose A looks
like. So, let me take a matrix A 1 1 1
1 2 5 just to
invent a matrix. So, there's a matrix A.
Notice that it has m = 3 rows and n = 2
columns.
Its rank is
The rank of that matrix is
two, right? Yeah, the columns are
independent.
Does AX = B
If I look at AX = B, so X is just X1 X2
and B is B1, B2, B3.
Do I expect to solve AX = B? What what's
No way, right? I mean
linear algebra is great, but solving
three equations with only two unknowns
usually we can't do it.
We can only solve it if this vector B is
what?
I can solve that equation if that vector
B1, B2, B3 is in the
column space. If it's a combination of
those columns, then fine. But usually it
won't be.
So the combinations just fill up a plane
and most vectors aren't on that plane.
So what I'm saying is that I'm going to
work with
the matrix A transpose A and I just want
to figure out in this example
what A transpose A is.
So it's 2 by 2. The first entry is a
three. The next entry is an eight.
This entry is a
What's that entry?
Eight. For sure.
We knew it had to be and this entry is
one. Now
getting out my trusty calculator.
30. Is that right?
30.
And is that matrix invertible? There's
an A transpose A.
And it is invertible, right? 38 is not a
multiple of 830 and and it's invertible.
And that's the normal That's what I
expect.
So
this is what I what I want to I want to
show.
It So here's the final Here's the key
point.
The null space
of A transpose A
It It It's not going to be always
invertible.
Tell me a matrix Yeah. Now, I I have to
I have to say that I can't say A
transpose A is always invertible.
Cuz that's asking too much. I mean, what
could the matrix A be, for example,
so that A transpose A was not
invertible?
Well, even could be the zero matrix. I
mean, that's like extreme case.
Suppose I
make this
rank
Suppose I change to that A.
Now, I figure out A transpose A again,
and I get What do I get?
I get nine.
I get nine, of course, and here I get
What's that entry?
27.
And is that matrix invertible? No.
And why do I I I I knew it wouldn't be
invertible anyway.
Cuz this matrix only has rank
one.
And if I have a product of matrices of
rank one, the product is not going to
have a rank bigger than one.
So, I'm not surprised that the answer
only has rank one, and that's what I'm
al- always happens.
That the rank of A transpose A comes out
to equal the rank of A.
So,
uh yeah. So, the null space of A
transpose A equals the null space of A.
The rank of A transpose A
equals the rank of A.
So,
let's
I'll I'll tell you
if in a
as soon as I can why that's true, but
let's
draw from that what the fact that I
want. This tells me that
this square symmetric matrix is
invertible
if
So, here's my conclusion. A transpose A
is invertible
if exactly when exactly if
this null space is
only got the zero vector.
Which means
the columns of A are independent.
So, A transpose A is invertible exactly
if A has
independent
columns.
That's the
That's the That's the the the fact that
I need about A transpose A, and then
you'll see next time
how A transpose A enters everything.
Next Next lecture is actually a crucial
one.
Here I'm preparing for it by
getting us thinking about A transpose A.
And its rank is the same as the rank of
A, and we can decide when it's
invertible.
Okay, so see you Friday.
Thank you.